Guide to the James E. Dyer Papers MS 052
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
- Series III: Political and Professional Career, RG6.xx___x
  - Subseries D: Politcal Career, RG6.xx___x
    - Correspondence (incoming) ALS C. Dodd, J. Lieberman, T. Moffett, 1985 (Box 71, Folder 1-8)
    - Danbury Democrats Salute James E. Dyer, October 18, 1985 (pewter plate and wine cup) (Box 95)
    - The Danbury Garden Club Certificate of Merit (15x24 framed), 1985 (Box OS 6)
    - Danbury Hospital's Centennial Year key ring "The Community Health Center, Stroock Tower", 1985 (Box 94)
    - Democratic Congressional Campaign Committee, Candidate Packet, 1985-1986 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Election "Elect Gene Tomanio, Mayor" poster, 1985 (Box OS 12)
    - Election memorabilia, 1985 (Box OS 12)
    - Form Letters, ca.1985 (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Issues - City-Federal Relations, 1985-1986 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Issues - Governor's Conference, 1985 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Issues - Market Data, Danbury, ca.1985 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - Issues - Say No to Drugs, 1985-1986 (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - Issues - Speeches, 1985 (Box 72, Folder 1-3)
    - Issues - Water Supply, 1985 (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - "Me run for a fourth term?? Well….." Berol USA (11x14 caricature of JD), 1985 (Box OS 12)
    - Mayor's Stationery, ca.1985 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Mayor's Proclamation Stationery, ca.1985 (Box OS 3)
    - Media/Civics (includes two Bill Seymour papers and SCSU 4/2000 working papers), 1985-1999 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Media - Live, 1985 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Notes and Remarks, ca.1985 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - "…No Other Place To Go" A Report of the Mayor's Task Force on the Homeless, 12/13/85, 1985 (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Oval glass plate with signature James Dyer, Mayor, 1985 (Box 95)
    - Oval glass plate engraved "Mayor & Mrs. James E. Dyer, September 15, 1985 (Box 95)
    - Planning, 1985 (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - Political Americana (Mondale/Ferraro election miscellany), 1985 (Box OS 12)
    - Press Releases, 1985 (Box 72, Folder 9-11)
    - Print Ads, 1985 (Box 66, Folder 15)
    - Proclamations (copies), 1985 (Box 66, Folder 16-19)
    - Research Ideas, 1985-1995 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Speech on Reform, 1985 (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - St. John's Church, Danbury, Essex (paperweight), ca.1985 (Box 94)
    - The Untold Story: Danbury's Unsung Role in the Revolution by Dorothy T. Schling (three copies), 1985 (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Ukranian Orthodox Church of America Insignia and Ribbon, ca.1985 (Box 94)
    - Welcome Posters from children in King Street School and Great Plain School, ca.1985 (Item 33)
    - Zippo Lighter with James E.Dyer Signature and City of Danbury Seal, ca.1985 (Box 94)
    - Annual Report (Remarks of Mayor James E. Dyer before the Greater Chamber of Commerce, December 18, 1986, Ridgewood Country Club) (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Budget Notes, 1986-1987 (Box 73, Folder 1-3)
    - Campaign '86 (State Elections), 1986 (Box 75, Folder 2-3)
    - Certificate of Appreciation from the Danbury Police Department (plaque), 1986 (Box 96)
    - Common Council Meeting Agenda and Minutes, September-October 1986 (Box 73, Folder 4-5)
    - Common Council Meeting Minutes, December 1986 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Connecticut Magazine, "Kid Mayors," August 1986 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence (mainly outgoing), 1986 (Box 75, Folder 5-14)
    - Correspondence (mainly incoming) ALS Gov. Wm.O'Neill, Chris Dodd, Joseph Lieberman, John Rowland, 1986 (Box 76, Folder 1-15)
    - Correspondence - Phil's Memos (Phil Capozzi, Administrative Assistant to the Mayor), 1986-1987 (Box 76, Folder 16-17)
    - Danbury Animal Welfare Society (plaque), 1985 (Box 96)
    - Danbury Fair Mall Opening, JD and AD, with Inscription Wayne Newton at Danbury Fair, October 19, 1986 (14x18 b/w photograh framed) (Box OS 1)
    - "Danbury Fair Mall", Intercorp, The Business Newspaper of Connecticut and Westchester County, July 25 - Aug. 7, 1986 (Box OS 11)
    - Danbury Fair Mall Opening, Invitation, 1986 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Danbury Fair Mall Opening Coaster, 1986 (Box 94)
    - "Dyer, Police, State of Indiana" (Sleeve Insignia), 1986 (Box 92)
    - "Elect Jim Dyer, Mayor Democrat, Pull Top Lever" 16x40 wood sign, 1986 (Item 27)
    - 40th Birthday Celebration (ALS Gov. O'Neill), 1986 (Box 77, Folder 2-5)
    - F. Francis D'Addario (Clippings), 1986 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Governor's Task Force On Accidental Toxic Chemical Releases, October 12, 1986 (Box 77, Folder 7-10)
    - Haz-Mat-S.E.R.C. (State Emergency Response Commission), 1986-1987 (Box 73, Folder 7-8)
    - Identification of Potential Chemical Hazards and Community Emergency Response Systems, City of Danbury, Connecticut, Community Emergency Response Steering Committee Report, May 1987. (maps removed to OS Box13), 1986-1987 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Ives Street Revitalization Area, Vol. Two, ca.1986 (Box OS 3)
    - Issues - AIDS, 1986 (Box 77, Folder 11-12)
    - Issues - Carbide, 1986 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Issues - Danbury 2000 (Speech Resources 11/86), 1986 (Box 73, Folder 10-12)
    - Issues - Department of Environmental Protection Suit, 1986-1987 (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Issues - Environment 2000, 1986 (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Issues - Paramedics, 1986-1987 (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Issues - Police Department, 1986 (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - Issues - State of the City, 1986 (Box 73, Folder 13-15)
    - The Mayors Of America's Principal Cities, July 1986 Directory (Box 90)
    - Memorial Day Parade "Dad-JD-AWD-Dodd" (VHS), 1986 (Box 91)
    - One day USA: a self-portrait of America's cities, edited by Richard and Judith Carver in association with the United States Conference of Mayors (book), 1986 (Box 90)
    - Press Releases, 1986 (Box 77, Folder 18-20)
    - Proclamations (copies), 1986 (Box 74, Folder 1-4)
    - The progressive city; planning and participation, 1969-1984 by Pierre Clavel, 1986 (Box 90)
    - Survey of City and Town Programs/Activities Commemorating Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Birthday, State of Connecticut, Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Holiday Commission, December 1986 (Booklet) (Box 77, Folder 21)
    - United Way Award for Outstanding Volunteer Service (plaque), undated (Box 96)
    - "Welcome to Danbury 'One of America's Best Places to Live'" 24x36 metal sign, 1986 (Item 28)
    - Absentee Ballot for town election 11/3/1987 (Box OS 12)
    - Active 9/87 (Contact Sheet removed to Photograph Collection), 1987 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Ads: Print '87, 1987 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Ads: Radio '87, 1987 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Brochure '87, 1987 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Budget and notes, 1987-1988 (Box 74, Folder 7-9)
    - Campaign Information and Remarks, 1987 (Box 78, Folder 3-6)
    - Chair WCSU Rocker presented to Ruth Haas upon her retirement in 1975, 1986 (Item 2)
      Plaque reads chair presented to Dr. Ruth A. Haas on her retirement 1975, presented to Mayor Jim Dyer 1986
    - Ch.3 News at 5:30, JED Mayor 10/87; Big Snow Storm (VHS), 1987 (Box 91)
    - Clippings November-December 1987 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Commissions, 1987 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Common Council Meting Agenda, April 1987 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Common Council Meeting Agenda and Minutes, June 1987 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Common Council Agenda and Notes, July 1987 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Common Council Meeting Agenda and Minutes, August 1987 (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Common Council Meeting Agenda and Minutes, September 1987 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Common Council Meeting Agenda and Minutes, October 1987 (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Common Council Meeting Agenda and Minutes, November 1987 (Minutes from JD's last Council Meeting) (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - Comune Di Decollatura, August 25th, 1987, Cultural Exchange With Provincia Di Catanzaro, Italy (11x17 poster), 1987-1997 (Box OS 12)
    - Correspondence (incoming) ALS Gov. William A. O'Neill, 1987 (Box 78, Folder 9-15)
    - Correspondence (outgoing), 1987 (Box 79, Folder 1-9)
    - Danbury Viet Nam Memorial Dedication, JD Main Speaker (VHS), ca.1987 (Box 91)
    - Debate #1 Election--Research, 1987 (Box 81, Folder 1-2)
    - Democratic Town Election, 1987 (Box 81, Folder 3- 5)
    - Direct Mail, 1987 (Box 81, Folder 6-7)
    - Drafts, Notes, Ideas, Platform, Ads, 1987 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Fairfield County 2000 Arts Task Force, Final Report, June, 1987 (Box 79, Folder 10-19)
    - Impact Forum, 1987 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Issues and Briefings, 1987 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Issues - Legislation 1987, 1985-1987 (Box 80)
    - Issues - Platform, 1987 (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - JD (posed) Three 20x30 and One 20x20 Color, 1987 (Box OS 13)
    - JFK's 70th Birthday, 1987 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Mayor's Briefing Book Updated to 1987 (Box 87)
    - The Mayor's Cookbook: What's Cooking at City Hall? The Favorite Recipes of over 300 Mayors Across the U.S.A. by the United States Conference of Mayors (signed by JD), 1987 (Box 90)
    - Mayor's Conference on Youth and Young Adult Substance Abuse, October 26, 1987 (Box 80, Folder 4-5)
    - Mayor's State of the City Address and Common Council Meeting, 1/6/1987 (VHS) (Box 91)
    - Memorial Day, 1987 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Materials, 1987 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Money Magazine, "Top 100 Places to Live", 1987-1989 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Planning '87, 1987 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Press Releases, 1987 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Primary Working Notes and Information, 1987 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Proclamations (copies), 1987 (Box 81, Folder 12-15)
    - Radio, 1987 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Recognition & Appreciation from Midwestern Connecticut Council on Alcoholism November 12, 1987 (plaque) (Box 95)
    - Republican Town Committee, 1987 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Senior Citizens Thank You Letter, 15x18 (Original watercolor by Vivian Cannavaro), 1987 (Box OS 4)
    - Speech Resources [1977-1987] (Box 81, Folder 16-17)
    - Taxpayer's Copy Of Danbury, Connecticut Revaluation Program, Oct. 1, 1987 (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Business digest (Danbury, Conn.) February 1988 and January 1989, 1988-1989 (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Clippings, 1988 (Box 80, Folder 15-18)
    - Correspondence (incoming), 1988-1989 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Ideas "IOWS" - 90s Writings/Preservation Skills, 1988-2000 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - JFK speech, draft, notes, November 22, 1988 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - NYU Class: City Governance: Issues, Policy and Reality, 1988-1989 (Box 82, Folder 4-7)
    - Bill of Rights (facsimlie) from Philip Morris Companies, Inc., 1989 (Box OS 5)
    - Clippings, 1989 (Box 82, Folder 8-13)
    - Media, 1989-1995 (Box 82, Folder 14-16)
    - NYU Class, 1989 (Box 83, Folder 1-7)
    - NYU Class, Final Papers & Grade Book (Closed), 1989 (Box 83, Folder 8-10)
    - NYU Part Time Faculty ID Card (SS# visible), 1989 (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - Associated Press Articles on Dyer Verdict, 1990 (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - Corruption Trial (JD Handwritten Notes), 1990 (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - Corruption Trial (Clippings), 1990 (Box 83, Folder 14-20)
    - Cotter, Cotter and Sohon/City Suit (Della Construction Company, Inc. vs. City of Danbury, et al), 1990-1991 (Box 84, Folder 1-3)
    - The News-Times, "Jury says Dyer didn't do it" February 10, 1990 (Box OS 10)
    - Salyut 6 Cyclogram; Information Design in Outer Space (chart), ca.1990 (Item 29)
    - Business digest (Danbury, Conn.) July 1, 1991 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence/Notes (Corruption Trial Verdict), 1991 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, Hugh F.Keefe/JD (The End), 1991 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, Incoming/Outing (ALS Lowell P. Weicker, Jr., Governor), 1991-1993 (Box 84, Folder 7-8)
    - CIA Factbook on Intelligence, Keane College 4/2/92, 1992 (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - Connecticut Defense Attorneys Speech, 1992 (Box 84, Folder 10-12)
    - Urban/Planning/City Issues, 1992-1994 (Box 84, Folder 13-15)
    - WLAD 10/1/93, 1993 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Cabranes, Judge Jose, 1994 (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - N.A.S.A. Hubble Space Telescope (poster), 1994 (Item 30)
    - Planning/Ed Ideas, 1994 (Box 85, Folder 3-4)
    - Seymour Class SCSU 11/94 "Media", 1994 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Buildings and Projects, 1990-1994 by Michael Graves (signed by author), 1995 (Box 89)
    - Clippings, 1995 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Lecture Spring 1995 [1971-1986] (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - 1995 Danbury Crossroads Main Street (newspaper supplement) (Box OS 13)
    - "The Suburbs" Danbury Comparative Data, 1995 (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - A Region at Risk by Robert D. Yao and Tony Hiss, 1996 (Box 88)
    - Clippings, 1996 (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Metropolis articles: What makes a neighborhood viable? and Dead Mall, 1996 (Box OS 5)
    - Clinton, Bill "Thank you for support….first term…" Letter, 1997 (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - Clippings, 1997 (Box 85, Folder 12-14)
    - Correspondence, New Jersey Institute of Technology, 1998-2008 (Box 85, Folder 15)
    - Bill Seymour's Class, 11/98, 1998 (Box 85, Folder 16)
    - Clinton, Bill, News-Times Articles 9/98, 1998 (Box 85, Folder 17)
    - Clippings, 1998 (Box 85, Folder 18)
    - Clinton, President Bill, News-Times Clippings, 1999 (Box OS 10)
    - Clippings, 1999 (Box 85, Folder 19)
    - "Grand Central Station" CBS Sunday Morning, CBS-TV Network (VHS), 1999 (Box 91)
    - Historical Danbury, News-Times clippings written by Bill Devlin [1900-2000], 1999-2000 (Box 85, Folder 20-22)
    - Historical Danbury, News-Times clippings writen by Bill Devlin [1900-2000] Originals, 1999-2000 (Box OS 10)
    - Archaic Landscape by Michael Graves, Iris Giclee Print and documentation 27/100 (11.25 x 11.25 color), 2000 (Box OS 3)
    - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 2000 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Media SCSU 4/20/2000 Lecture and Media Research (see also NYU Lecture notes on the media), 2000-2003 (Box 86, Folder 3-5)
    - New-Times articles on N.Y. Yankees, George W. Bush election, and New York Times article on 2001 Inaugural, 2000-2001 (Box OS 10)
    - Boughton Mayor Campaign, 2001 (Box 86, Folder 6-7)
    - The Chronicle Review, "The Fractured Landscape, Reflections on September 11, 2001 and It's Aftermath" (Box OS 5)
    - Clippings/Speeches, 2001-2004 (Box 86, Folder 8-11)
    - Buildings and Projects, 1995-2003 by Michael Graves (soft cover book, signed by author), 2002 (Box 89)
    - Michael Graves designs, the art of the everyday object by Phil Patton with Michael Graves Group, 2004 (Box 89)
    - Chamber of Commerce: Leadership Danbury 2006, Notes (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - Chamber of Commerce: Leadership/Planning Event 1/19/2006 (Box 86, Folder 13-16)
    - Chamber of Commerce: Leadership Danbury 2007, 2008, and 2009 Research Notes, 2007-2009 (Box 86, Folder 17-18)
    - JD presentation 12/22/07 revised (CD), 2007 (Box 91)
    - Chamber 1/24/08 Revised (CD), 2008 (Box 91)
    - Election Briefing Articles/Notes, 2008 (Box 86, Folder 19)
    - Unitarian Universalist Congregation of Danbury, 2008 (Box 86, Folder 20)
    - Original Clippings, ca. 1960-2004 (Box 98-100)